thorne.com 2016-10-26

# Privacy Policy | Thorne Research

Thorne Research has a longstanding commitment to safeguard the privacy of the information entrusted to us from health-care practitioners, patients, and customers. The privacy principles and procedures set forth in this Website Privacy Policy are intended to tell you how this information is collected, used, and distributed via our websites.

### Types and Uses of Personal Information

When you use our websites, information that personally identifies you may be collected and processed by Thorne Research employees.  Usually, the only information collected will be your name, business address, mailing address, telephone number, fax number, e-mail address, and professional licensing information when you knowingly provide this information.  In addition, this information may be collected as a result of the services or the products you request information about or purchase from us.  Finally, Thorne Research may collect or process personally identifiable information, such as your Internet domain or IP address, as part of the normal operation of our websites, or during the normal course of your activities on or use of our websites.  In nearly all cases this data is collected or processed by, or transferred to, Thorne Research's corporate headquarters in Sandpoint, Idaho.  When you use our websites you are consenting to the collection, processing, transfer, or use of this information.  If you choose not to consent to the collection, processing, transfer, or use of this information, then you should not use, or you should discontinue using, our websites.

### Personal Information Shared with Third Parties

Without a user's express consent, Thorne Research will not sell, trade, or disclose a user's personally identifiable information to any third party who would attempt to market products or services to the user.  However, Thorne Research may disclose information to a third party that is used to assist carrying out a transaction for you or providing a service to you (for example, packaging, sending, or delivering a purchase or information to you or clearing a credit card transaction).

Thorne Research might be required to disclose information about users of our websites as a result of a subpoena, a search warrant, or some other legal process authorized by a court of law.  In addition, Thorne Research might disclose information about users of our websites to a third party who is assisting us in conducting an investigation about unauthorized activity that constitutes a violation of the policies for using our websites, or when circumstances dictate the need to protect or defend our rights or property.

### Security Measures

Thorne Research regularly implements industry-recommended technological and operational security processes for the purpose of protecting personally identifiable information from unauthorized access, loss, misuse, alteration, or unintentional destruction.  Although no security measure can absolutely guarantee against unauthorized uses, Thorne Research regularly reviews and updates our website security measures for the purpose of providing appropriate security for personally identifiable information.

### Access and Accuracy

Thorne Research only wants to maintain accurate information about the users of our websites.  You can request to be provided the individual information that has been gathered about you by contacting Thorne Research (see the Contact Information section below).  Upon receiving proper identification information, Thorne Research will provide you the personally identifiable information that is maintained about your use of Thorne Research's websites, or which you have supplied to Thorne Research via Thorne Research's websites.  If you find a factual inaccuracy, then you can notify Thorne Research and the inaccuracy will be corrected.

### Data Retention

Thorne Research will not retain your personally identifiable information longer than is necessary for the purpose it was collected.

### Children's Privacy

Thorne Research's policy is that children under the age of 18 should not send any personally identifiable information to Thorne Research's websites without a parent's or guardian's consent.  Thorne Research encourages parents and guardians to instruct children about the safe and responsible use of personally identifiable information on the Internet.  Thorne Research will not knowingly collect, use, or disclose to any third party any personally identifiable information collected from children under the age of 18.

### Linked Websites

Thorne Research may provide links from our websites to third-party websites.  However, because Thorne Research does not control these third-party websites, you should always review the privacy policy of these third-party websites.  Thorne Research is not responsible for the privacy policy or practices of third-party websites or for services controlled by other companies or organizations.

### Use of Cookies and Pixel Tags

When you browse this website, one or more temporary cookies may be placed on your computer to help Thorne Research collect information to better understand your interests and to better serve you.  Cookies are used on most major websites.  What are "cookies?"  Cookies are small bits of information stored by your web browser's software on your computer's hard drive or temporarily in your computer's memory.  Using cookies is an industry standard.  Cookies enhance a user's experience and access to information on a website.  Cookies enable Thorne Research to recognize you and personalize your experience on this website.

Thorne Research may use cookies for a variety of purposes including, but not limited to:  e-commerce functions, to recognize user access or log-on privileges, to track usage and traffic patterns, to provide information and advertisements for goods or services that might interest a user based on the user's use of this website, and to track the number of users who visit and use this website.

Although most web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, you can decline the placement of cookies on your hard drive by using the appropriate feature of your web browser software (if available) to delete cookies.  You can also refuse cookies as part of your browser settings, but doing so might inhibit your ability to utilize many of the features on this and other websites you visit.

In addition to using cookies, Thorne Research websites might employ "pixel tracking" a common process that is used in connection with advertisements and/or internal tracking.  Pixel tracking involves the use of pixel tags – an invisible tag that is placed on various pages of a website that tracks a user's activity.  Pixel tags are not visible to users and consist of a few lines of computer code.  Pixel tracking measures the effectiveness of advertisements by compiling aggregate and specific usage statistics.  Thorne Research can access pixel tags to identify the activities and interests that better enable us to match products, services, and offers to the user's interests and needs.  For example, if a user visits another Thorne Research website as a result of an advertisement on another website, then the pixel tag will allow the advertiser to track that its advertisement brought the user to a website operated by Thorne Research.  If a user visits a website or other online system operated by Thorne Research, and the user is linked to another website, then Thorne Research also is able to determine that the user was sent to and/or interacted with a third-party website.  This data is collected for use in marketing and research.

If you wish to opt-out of Google Analytics entirely when visiting this or any other website that utilizes this service, or interest-based advertising, then visit the Network Advertising Initiative at: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>.  Or if you wish to specifically choose not to send information to Google Analytics about your visit to this website, then you can do so by going to: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

### Contact Information

You may direct comments, complaints, or questions regarding this Website Privacy Policy to Thorne Research's Information Technology Department at:  [info@thorne.com](mailto:info@thorne.com)

### Modifications to Policy

Thorne Research reserves the right to change, modify, or update this Website Privacy Policy at any time with or without notice, and to make that policy effective immediately for information we already have about you, as well as future information that we may obtain about you.

Thorne Research always indicates below the date of the current Website Privacy Policy so users will know when it was last updated.  To make this policy easy to find, the most current copy will be accessible from clicking the Privacy Policy link on the home page.

Last updated:  5 March 2015
